Nice of you to come.
I welcome you.
You don't look very welcoming.
I am he who was entrusted to guard this place.
For the time being,
you may call me Number 48.
Number 48?
It's been so long. I'm delighted to be able to go against someone so capable.
You have run out of luck
by coming up against me.
Do not think ill of me, kid.
And you, don't think ill of me for being the kid who defeated you.
Nice. You move well for your size.
That's more like it.
Who are you?!
I should respond when
asked who I am, huh?
My name is Number 66.
Although, that's just what they call me at work.
Number 66?
Yes. I do have my own, proper name as well,
but if you heard it, you'd be
so surprised you'd wet yourself.
I'll tell you when I finish you off.
His reflexes...
Why, you!
What?!
You brat!
He's...
the same kind of armored body as Al?!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
I knew it.
Just as I thought, you're hollow.
Surprising. You've done well to realize it.
I spar against someone like you all the time.
I could tell by
the way you moved.
There's someone like me
in the outside world, is there?
It bugs me to think
that there's some idiot besides me who
thought of bonding a soul to a suit of armor.
Fascinating.
Allow me to reintroduce myself.
"Number 48" is the label I had as a condemned prisoner.
Officially, I'm supposed to have been executed two years ago.
A condemned prisoner?
Which means that, sure enough, there's a connection
between the 5th Laboratory here and the prison next door.
When I had a flesh-and-blood body,
I was called "The Slicer."
I was a mass murderer,
who caused many public disturbances.
Nowadays, my skills have been called upon,
and I am the immortal watchdog over this place.
No, you're not immortal.
What?
Your bloodseal!
The iron within the blood is attuned with the metal of your armor,
and that is what keeps your soul
bound to this world.
If that seal is broken, you'll die.
It appears that after all this time,
I've encountered someone with a little backbone.
This should prove to be an interesting fight.
Your weak spot
has been exposed.
If you're going to surrender, now's the time.
I don't care!
I'm the type who seeks a little tension in battle, you see.
Now then...
En garde!
What was that? Just now there was something strange in my shoulder...
Since it's less heavy,
its strength has dropped as well,
so make sure you don't do anything reckless.
I have to finish this quickly, or I'm in trouble!
Just like a monkey, aren't you?
Hey, what'd you say?!
It's been ages since I've had
such responsive prey. I'm delighted.
However, judging by your wound and your exhaustion,
the end of this battle is in sight.
As you can see,
my body knows no fatigue.
Surrender. Right now, my companion is disposing of your partner outside.
You can't rely on him to help you.
Hey, this companion
of yours—is he strong?
He's strong although not to
the same extent as myself.
What's so funny?
In that case,
I don't need to worry.
I've been sparring with him
for a long time, but I've never won.
Why, you...
Hold still so I can chop you up!
You miserable behemoth!
I'm going to hurt you
for all you're worth!
So you tell me...
Now!
I'm taking a shoulder roast!
Now you've gone and done it.
My head fell off.
Your body...
Yeah. Thanks to certain circumstances, I've wound up with this body.
You can't tell who I am, can you?
Don't tell me you've forgotten.
Thanks to you guys catching me,
I was made a condemned criminal, after all.
Number 66 was my label on death row.
When I still had a flesh-and-blood body, the name people called me by was...
the serial killer, Barry the Chopper!
Barry the Chopper?
Barry? You mean, from back then?!
That's right!
After being caught and executed,
I've come back from the depths of hell
to take revenge against you!
You don't say.
Don't "you don't say" me!
People get surprised when
an executed prisoner is still alive, you know!
And what's more, when a beheaded suit of armor still moves around,
you should be more like "Gyaah!"
or like "Waah!" or like "What's the deal with your body?!" or like...
Gyaah! What's the deal
with your body?!
That's awful. You'll hurt my feelings, you know.
Are you a fellow
executed prisoner too?
I'm no criminal!
Even so, now that I know, this fight is all mine.
I know what your weakness is!
If I destroy the bloodseal within
that armor someplace, you will die.
Brace yourself!
The same goes for you too, right?
Yeah, but you don't know
where my bloodseal is, do you?!
And you don't know
where mine is, do you?
At this point,
I'll just have to slice you up and
find out where your bloodseal is!
What's with him? Jeez...
B Block and C Block have both turned up nothing.
He must still be in the area somewhere! Find him, whatever it takes!
Yes, sir!
He's pretty bold to be staging an attack on a military facility like this.
Still, why is Scar so preoccupied with coming after Edward-san?
So then, where are
the Elric brothers?
Uh, yeah, well, you see...
It's like this...
You're acting suspiciously!
Major Armstrong!
With your authorization,
could I have the forces here relocate?
What do you mean?
The Elric brothers are currently
at the Central 5th Laboratory.
Tell me more.
What's the matter?
Your movements are growing poorer.
Are you through already, Pee-Wee?
Who are you calling too small to even see, who doesn't even make for a good target?!
At least your spirits are high.
But I wonder how much longer that will last!
Not the Automail again!
You're open!
You hold me in too low a regard.
Did you think you could best me
from a spear's distance?
Ridiculous!
You've done well to have fought this long. However, you have reached your limits.
Resign yourself.
There is no way you can win now.
We'll see about that.
You're forgetting that I'm not alone.
Now, Al!
When did you get in here?!
What?!
That's not fair!
All is fair in battle.
What's wrong?
My bloodseal is not yet broken.
If your soul is in your head,
then once I cut it off,
your body is just a hunk of iron.
There's no reason to
fight you any longer.
Never mind that, there's something I wanted to ask you.
The Philosopher's Stone?
If you've come to investigate this place, there is little else you could be after.
In that case,
we can cut to the chase.
Why don't you tell me
everything you know about it?
I can't tell you.
What?!
Hey, beaten dogs
don't get to show me up.
I'll break your bloodseal!
I haven't lost yet.
That's...
impossible!
One set of armor isn't necessarily limited to one soul, you know.
The body has a bloodseal as well?
Are you okay,
my older brother?
Yeah, just barely,
my younger brother.
Younger brother?
Did I forget to mention that?
The mass murderer known as the Slicer...
was a pair of mass-murdering brothers!
An independent head and body, huh?
That reeks of foul play!
Who was it that said
"All is fair in battle"?
How dare you injure my brother!
You're going to pay for that, Pipsqueak!
Don't call me Pipsqueak!
Don't underestima—
Whoa, I'm not giving you any time to transmute!
I'm losing too much blood.
I'm seriously starting to get lightheaded.
This is serious trouble.
Am I going to die here?
Dammit!
If I die here...
who's going to return
Al back to normal?!
How dare you
do that to my brother!
I can do that too!
I won't give you
enough time to transmute!
I just remembered that nasty fellow.
What is this?!
He didn't perform transmutation,
just the decomposition technique?
Sorry about that.
I can't die just yet.
Dammit! Now you've gone and done it, you dirty brat!
Ick!
Why, you! Dammit!
I deserve better than this!
Damn. Brother...
As much as it pains me,
we've lost, Brother.
Don't tell me that there's
actually three of you brothers.
No, no.
Well done, kid.
This time, you truly are victorious.
Well then, this time,
tell me everything you know.
I cannot tell you.
Now, destroy us at once.
What?
Nothing remains for the defeated except death.
That is our rule.
I'm not about to kill anyone.
Hmph! You're far too generous!
With our bodies like this,
can you possibly call us "someone"?
I didn't tell you to kill us.
I told you to destroy us.
Come on!
If I were to concede that you aren't people,
I'd... I'd have to concede
that my younger brother,
Al, is not a person either.
Your younger brother?
Dammit!
Hasn't this gone on long enough, already?
I'm concerned about Brother.
Brother?
That pipsqueak alchemist
is your brother?
Brother gets angry
if you mention his height.
Ah, I see...
What?
So it was your brother who
gave you that armored form!
That's right. He risked
his life to transmute me.
That's rich!
What's so funny?!
Oh, how rude of me.
Brotherly love is so beautiful...
Even if it is false affection.
False?
That's right! False love!
That's not so!
My brother genuinely loves me!
What a perfectly naïve fellow you are.
Suppose you were an imitation. What would you do then?
Suppose your personality and memories
were implanted in you as it suited
your brother. What would you do then?
Th-That just isn't so!
I am, without question, a person, whose name is Alphonse Elric!
As a spirit—something indefinite,
which cannot be seen with the eye—
how are you to prove that?
Your brother—and the people around you—
could all be deceiving you.
That's...
That's not...
My brother is a person,
and you guys are people too.
I don't want...
to kill you.
Brother?
Amusing... Quite amusing...
For as long as I can remember,
my brother and I have made our lives
by stealing, breaking, killing, and being looked down upon as fiends and brutes.
Now that we've abandoned our bodies, to say nothing of our hearts and minds,
to think that, for the first time,
we're being treated as people...
It's so amusing!
I'm a person!
I'm Alphonse Elric!
Do you have any proof that you ever really existed?
Where is your body?
Huh?!
Well, it's...
It can't be...
For all of it to be false...
That couldn't possibly be...
Listen, Al...
There's something... I've been meaning to say to you for a long time...
but I've been too scared...
and I haven't been able to say it.
What is it?
What was Brother trying to tell me?
What was it that
he was too scared to...
too scared to tell me?
Brother!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 21: "The Red Glow"
If there's a color to people's lives...
that's probably the color it would be.